The album that changed it all.
Thriller 40 is a documentary, music film directed by Nelson George.
Forty years after the release of Michael Jackson’s ‘Thriller,’ the best-selling album of all-time, director Nelson George takes
fans back in time to the making of a pop masterpiece, featuring never-before-seen footage and candid interviews.
Self (archive footage), played by Michael Jackson.
Self (archive footage), played by Quincy Jones.
Self (archive footage), played by Paul McCartney.
Self, played by Usher.
Self, played by Mary J. Blige.
Self, played by Mark Ronson.
Thriller 40 is a 2023 documentary film about the 40th
anniversary of Michael Jackson's 1982 album Thriller.
The film, directed by Nelson George, was released in
the United States on December 2, 2023.
It aired on Showtime and was streamed on
Paramount+ only for Showtime subscribers.
Internationally, it debuted the same day in the U.K., Australia, Canada, Italy,
France, Germany, Switzerland, Austria, Latin America, and South Korea.
On October 27, 2023, the trailer for the documentary was released.
A 40th-anniversary edition reissue of Thriller (1982)
of the same title was released in 2022.